Wertheimer, Barbara Additional Files 6144
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Barbara Wertheimer Additional Files
1971-1990
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Wertheimer, Barbara
6144
2.5 cubic feet
2.5 linear ft.
Records.
5819043
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 12, 2004
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 23, 2016
Biographical / Historical
Barbara Mayer Wertheimer (1926-September 23, 1983) was an American labor historian and labor organizer from the 1940s through the early 1980s.
From 1947 to 1948 Ms. Wertheimer was an organizer and acting education director for the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America. She worked briefly for the American Labor Education Service and then from 1961 to 1966 as a consultant for the New York State Division of Housing and Community Renewal. In 1966 Ms. Wertheimer joined the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations at Cornell University. While at Cornell she was a senior extension associate, director of the Trade Union Women's Studies program, and, from 1977 on, an associate professor and director of the Institute for Women and Work, which she cofounded. Ms. Wertheimer remained at Cornell until her death in 1983.
Ms. Wertheimer is well known for her monograph "We Were There: The Story of Working Women in America" (1977).
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4015: Barbara Wertheimer Office Files 5729: Barbara Wertheimer Research Files 5736: Barbara Wertheimer Additional Files 5736 P: Barbara Wertheimer Photographs 6144 AV: Barbara Wertheimer Collection of Audio Recordings
Women labor union members; Arbitration, Industrial; Newman, Pauline; Wertheimer, Barbara; Coalition of Labor Union Women (U.S.) -- Archives; United Food and Commercial Workers International Union
5819043
- CLUW Publicity (Coalition for Labor Union Women), 1973-1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- The Empowerment of Union Women Project, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- CLUW East Coast Conference, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Scope and Contents
  8-Dec-73
- CLUW Founding Conference, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  March 23-24, 1974
- CLUW Constitutional Convention, Detroit, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  December 5-7, 1975
- CLUW Programs-Awards Dinners, 1971-1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- CLUW Legislative and Coalition Network Building Conference, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  3/26-27/81
- CLUW Workshop on Sex Discrimination, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  9-Nov-74
- CLUW Resolutions, 1974-1977 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- CLUW Conference, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- CLUW Conference, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  September 15-18, 1977
- Resolutions and Proceedings, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  1977 CLUW Convention
- CLUW Issues & Activities, 1973-1980 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Notes from B. Wertheimer for the article "New Approaches to Collective Power: Four Working Women's Organization," by Nancy Seifer & Barbara Wertheimer in Women Organizing, ed. by Bernice Cummings & Victoria Schuck, Scarecrow Press, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- UFCW (United Food & Commercial Workers) Women's Affairs and Civil Rights Conference, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Alice Cook Materials, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- CLUW Eastern Chapters, 1974-1977 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- CLUW Midwest Chapters, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- CLUW Southern Chapters, 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- CLUW West Coast Chapters, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- CLUW Local Chapters NYCLUW (New York Coalition for Labor Union Women, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- CLUW Local Chapters NYCLUW, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Local Chapters NYCLUW, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- CLUW Local Chapters NYCLUW, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- CLUW Local Chapters NYCLUW, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- CLUW Local Chapters NYCLUW, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- CLUW Long Island Chapter, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- CWA (Communications Workers of America) Conference and Courses, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- CLUW Evaluation Form, Correspondence, Addresses, Project Opportunity Newsletters, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- NYS CLUW Conference, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  Oct-81
- CLUW National Executive Board Meetings/Mailings Folder 1, 1976-1979 (Box 2, Folder 31a)
- CLUW National Executive Board Meetings/Mailings Folder 2, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 31b)
- CLUW National Executive Board Meetings/Mailings Folder 3, 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 31c)
- CLUW Publications and Pamphlets, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- CLUW Publications, 1973-1990 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- CLUW Statement of Purpose, Structure and Guidelines, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- CLUW Constitution, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- CLUW Membership, 1974-1980 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- "The Cost of Pay Equity in Public and Private Employment", National Committee on Pay Equity, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Damage Report-The Decline of Equal Employment Opportunity Enforcement under the Reagan Administration, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Women, Work and the Law / Conference on Equal Pay ND (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Comparable Worth, Oakland California, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Comparable Worth, 1985-1987 (Box 2, Folder 41a)
- Comparable Worth, 1979-1987 (Box 2, Folder 41b)
- Comparable Worth/Pay Equity, 1980-1984 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Comparable Worth-AFSCME, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- CSEA Convention Workshop. Correspondence., 1978 (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Training Minority Womens Program Course Materials. Part II. (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Women. Affirmative Action., 1972-1978 (Box 3, Folder 46)
- Spokeswoman. Proposals and Correspondence., 1972 (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Midwest Academy Funding Proposal., 1972 (Box 3, Folder 48)
- Cantarow, Ellen. Vita., 1973 (Box 3, Folder 49)
- Magarik, Larry L. Vita., 1973 (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Steele, Richard W. Vita. (Box 3, Folder 51)